Guide to the Cooper Bridge Plan collection, 1887-1889 (bulk)
Cooper Bridge collection, 1887-1889 (bulk)
- Series III. Drawings, Prints, Blueprints
  - McCallum Truss Bridge. Lanesboro, Pa., 1851; 37.5 x 30.5; Print (Folder 76)
    McCallum Truss Bridge. Lanesboro. N.Y. & E.R.R. Clear span 190 ft. Length of trusses 200 ft. out to out. Built 1851
  - Middle Island Creek Bridge, Undated (Folder 12)
    North Western Virginia Railroad
  - Milholland's boiler plate girder bridge, 1882; 28 x 22; Blueprint (Folder 24)
    Earliest Boiler Plate Girder Bridge as originally erected on the Baltimore & Susquehanna Railroad now the Northern Central Railway, 1846-47 By its designer James Milholland of Baltimore MD
  - Milholland's boiler plate girder bridge, 1882; 30.5 x 26; Print (Folder 24)
  - Mohawk Bridge, 1804; 36 x 10; 2 copies; Rough pen-and-ink sketch on vellum (Folder 34)
    Plan for the Mohawk Bridge at Schenectady" [with notations: Theodore Burr and James Murdoch [ARB Pl. VIII]
  - Monongahela River bridge, 1852; 24 x 19; Print (Folder 6)
    Iron Bridge Over the Monongahela River on the Baltimore & Ohio R.Rd [ARB Pl. XIII]
  - New Hope bridge, Undated (Folder 9)
    Bridge over the Delaware at New Hope
  - New York Central & Hudson R. RR ... bridge ... Bronx R., Undated; 16 x 29; 40 x 29.5; Print in two pieces (Folder 86 a,b)
    N.Y.C. & H.R.R.R. Harlem Div. Bridge No. 48 over Bronx River
  - New York Central & Hudson R. RR ... bridge ... Castleton Station, 1892-08-04; 35.5 x 19.5; Print (Folder 40)
    N.Y.C. and H.R.R.R. Bridge No. 341 near Castleton Station
  - New York Central & Hudson R. RR ... bridge ...Erie Canal, Canastota, 1865; 36 x 30; 40 x 30; Print in two pieces (Folder 40)
    N.Y.C. & H.R.R.R. Double Track, Riveted Lattice Bridge over the Erie Canal at Canastota, N.Y.
  - New York Central & Hudson R. RR ... bridge ... Genesee River, Rush Junction, 1892-09-13; 28 x 27; 27 x 27; Print in two consecutive pieces (Folder 90 a,b)
    New York Central & Hudson River R.R., Can. & N. Falls Branch, Bridge #P30 over Genesee River near Rush Junction
  - New York Central & Hudson R. RR ... bridge ... Kinderhook Creek at Stockport, Undated; 27 x28; 24.5 x 28; Print in two consecutive pieces (Folder 95 a,b)
    N.Y.C. & H.R.R.R. Hudson River Division Bridge #307 over Kinderhook Creek at Stockport, N.Y.
  - New York, Lake Erie & Western RR ... bridge over Susquehanna, 1891; 19.5 x 30.5; 37 x 20.5; Print in two pieces (Folder 77 a,b)
    N.Y.L.E. & W.R.R.. Bridge No. 73 Susquehanna Div.
  - New York, Lake Erie & Western RR ... miles of track, 1888-09-30; 29 x 17.5; Blueprint (Folder 36)
    Miles of track owned, leased, and operated by the N.Y.L.E. & W.R.R.Co
  - Norfolk, Va. Fink bridges on the Norfolk & Petersburg RR, Undated (Folder 10)
  - Ohio River Bridge, Henderson, Kentucky, Undated; 44 x 7; Blueprint (Box 2)
    General design. Ohio River bridge. Henderson Ky
  - Ohio River Bridge, Louisville, Kentucky, 1868; 22 x 17; Lithograph on thin paper (Folder 8)
    400 Feet Span of the Ohio River Bridge at Louisville, Ky. [ARB Pl.XVIII]
  - Patent bridge “Colossus”, Undated; 18 x 17; Print on vellum (Folder 2)
  - Patent bridge "Colossus” [composite], Undated; 40 x 27.2; 2 copies; Print (Folder 49)
    11 individual plans, 8 of which also appear as separate pieces elsewhere in the collection; the 2 others are: "Schuylkill Permanent Bridge, built by Timothy Palmer" and "Patent Bridge 'Colossus' across the River Schuylkill at Philadelphia, built by Lewis Wernwag." [part of ARB Pl. IX]
  - Pecos River Viaduct, Goelzsch-Thal Viaduct; Kinzua Viaduct, 1888-04-26; 22 x 20; Blueprint (Folder 20)
    Pecos River Viaduct (Texas - Galveston, Harrisburg, & San Antonio Rail Road)
  - Pecos River Viaduct, 1893; 14 x 25; 36 x 25; 39 x 25; 3 copies each; Print in three consecutive pieces (Folder 20)
    Untitled diagram identical to the other set of Pecos River Viaduct
  - Pecos River Viaduct, details, 1891; 27 x 24 (Folder 96 a,b)
    Pecos River Viaduct. Galveston, Harrisburg & San Antonio RR
  - Penn Bridge and Machine Works, Undated; 24 x 16.5; Lithograph (Folder 7)
    Penn Bridge and Machine Works. New Brighton, Pa. T. B. White and Sons. Proprietors
  - Petersburg, Virginia, Fink bridges on the Norfolk & Petersburg RR, Undated (Folder 10)
  - Pittsburg, Cincinnati & St. Louis RR bridge, chord bars, 1888-12; 19 x 5; Blueprint (Folder 38)
    Channel Span: Bridge No. 30- P.C. & St. L. Ry. - Plan of Chord Bars
  - Pittsburg, Cincinnati & St. Louis RR bridge, truss diagram, 1888-12-04; 38 x 17.5; Blueprint (Folder 38)
    Channel Span of Bridge 30: P.C. & St. L. Ry. Chief Engineers Office
  - Portage Viaduct (timber), 1852; 33 x 30.5; 23 x 30.5 (Folder 69 a,b)
    Viaduct across the Genesee River at Portage, N.Y. Buffalo and New York City Railroad
  - Post’s patent diagonal truss combination bridge, Undated; 40 x 26.5; Print (Folder 52)
    Post's patent diagonal truss combination bridge
  - Post’s patent diagonal truss iron bridge, 1860; 40 x 26.5; Lithograph on thick paper (Folder 53)
    Post's patent diagonal truss iron bridge
  - Post's truss bridge, New York and Erie RR, 1865; 37.5 x 30.5; Print (Folder 78)
    First Example Post's Truss Bridge. South Washingtonville, N.Y. Newburgh Branch, N.Y. & E.R.R.
  - Pratt truss bridge, over Merrimac River, Eastern RR, 1877-04; 45 x 28; Drawing (Folder 55)
    Plan of Draw, Newburyport Bridge, Eastern Railroad
  - Pratt truss bridge, over Merrimac River, Eastern RR, 1877; 37 x 30; Print (Folder 79)
    Pratt Truss Bridge over the Merrimac River at Newburyport, Mass. on the Eastern Railroad
  - Rockville Bridge (wooden arch), Pennsylvania RR, 1849; 37.5 x 30.5; 24.5 x 30.5; Print in two consecutive pieces (Folder 85 a,b)
    Pensylvania [sic] Railroad Bridge over the Susquehanna River at Rockville
  - Salmon River bridge, Columbia Bridge, 1849; 36 x 31; Print (Folder 61)
    Bridge across Salmon River Malone N.Y. Northern Railroad
  - Schuylkill Permanent Bridge, Easton Bridge; Patent Bridge “Colossus,” and Wernwag’s bridges, Undated; 25 x 13; Color drawing (Folder 28)
    Schuylkill Permanent Bridge [ARB Pl. IV]
  - Simpsons Creek Bridge, Undated (Folder 12)
    Fink triangular truss bridges, North Western Virginia RR
  - Steubenville Bridge, channel span, 1963; 40.45 x 30.5; Print (Folder 81)
    Channel Span Steubenville Bridge. Built 1863-64. Designed by J. H. Linville C.E.
  - Steubenville Bridge, details of end posts, 1863; 16.5 x 18.5; Blueprint (Folder 45)
    Details of end posts Spans 1-2-3 & 5 to 8 - Steubenville bridge
  - Steubenville Bridge, details of front posts, 1853-06-13; 35 x 25.5; Blueprint (Folder 45)
    Steubenville Bridge Span No. 4 Details of front posts
  - Sulphur Fork Bridge, Undated (Folder 12)
    Fink triangular truss bridges, Louisville & Nashville RR
  - Suspension truss bridge, Troy & Greenfield RR, Undated; 27 x 18 (Folder 27)
    Suspension truss bridge as designed for the Troy & Greenfield R. R. by H. Haupt C. E.
  - Susquehanna River bridge, Baltimore & Ohio RR, 1894-01-17; 67 x 9; Blueprint (Box 2)
    General Design for Susquehanna River Bridge Philadelphia Branch B. & O. R.Rd.
  - Susquehanna River bridge, New York & Erie RR, 1849; Print (Folder 89)
    Bridge over East Branch of Susquehanna River. Section 179. Susquehanna Division. N. Y. & E. R. R
  - Tennessee River bridge, (Fink), 1866; 22.5 x 17.5; 3 copies; Lithograph on thin paper (Folder 15)
    Bridge over Tennessee River on the Memphis and Charleston R.R. at Decatur, Ala.
  - Tigarts Valley Bridge, Undated (Folder 12)
  - Town lattice truss, Undated; 20 x 21; 2 copies; Print (Folder 22)
    3 views: cross-section; side elevation; plan [ARB Pl. X]
  - Town lattice truss, 1861; 26 x 18; Color print (Folder 26)
    Railroad bridge over the Hudson at Troy, N.Y.
  - Town lattice truss (wooden), 1851; 37.5 x 30.5; Print (Folder 87)
    Town's Lattice Bridge over the Hudson River at Troy, N.Y.
  - Tray Run Viaduct, 1853; 32 x 30.5; 38 x 30.5; Print in two consecutive pieces (Folder 92 a,b)
    Tray Run Viaduct. Baltimore and Ohio Railroad.
  - Trenton (arch) Bridge, 1869; 36 x 24; 2 copies; Print on gray pape (Folder 50)
    Built 1804; reconstructed 1848 and 1869; Theodore Burr, engineer. [ARB Pl. VII]
  - Trenton Falls Bridge, full view, 1891-08; 40 x 30.5; Print (Folder 88)
    Trenton Falls Bridge 200' Span, A. & St. L.R.R.
  - Trenton Falls Bridge, truss details, 1891-08; 33 x 30.5; 27. x 30.5; Print in two continuous pieces (Folder 84 a,b)
    Trenton Falls Bridge 200'-0" Span
  - Turkey Creek bridge, Louisville & Nashville RR, 1888-01-28; 37.5 x 34.5; Blueprint (Folder 57 a)
    Detailed diagrams of posts, joints, cross ties, stringers, chords, etc.
  - Turkey Creek bridge, 1888-02-02; 42.5 x 34; Blueprint (Folder 57 b)
    Other Details
  - Turnhole bridge, Undated (Folder 43)
    Lehigh Coal and Navigation Company
  - Waterford Bridge, 1804; 42 x 11.5; Drawing (Folder 56)
    Highway Bridge Over the Hudson River Between Waterford and Lansingburgh, Built of hewn yellow pine in 1804. Finished Nov 30, 1804; covered in 1814
  - Waterford Bridge, spans, 1814; ca. 32 x 18; 3 copies; Blueprints (Folder 42)
  - Waterford Bridge (presumptive), 1895-08; ca. 18 x 16; Blueprints (Folder 16)
    Cross Sections
  - Wernwag's bridges, 1814; 24.5 x 19; Lithograph (Folder 9)
    Five bridges, including plans of three: "Bridge over the Delaware at New Hope" [blt. 1814]; "Patent Bridge Colossus, across the Schuylkill at Philadelphia" [blt. 1812]; and "Bridge Economy, the Principle of which is across Neshaminy, on the Post Road from Philadelphia to N. York & over Frankfort Creek" [blt. 1810]; plus complete elevations of two covered bridges: "Upper Ferry or Lancaster Schuylkill Bridge" and "Schuylkill Permanent Bridge"; "Lewis Wernwag" and "Drawn & Engraved by E. G. Gridley" [cf. ARB Pl. IX]
  - Wheeling Creek bridge, 1860; 25.5 x 19.5; Print (Folder 23)
    Bridge over Wheeling Creek on Baltimore & Ohio Rail Road
  - Whipple-Murphy Iron Bridge, Illinois Central RR, 1859; 26 x 30.5; 23 x 30.5; 20.5 x 30.5; 27.5 x 30.5; Print in four pieces (Folder 99 a,b,c,d)
    Whipple Iron Bridge built for the Illinois Central R. R. by A. & P. Roberts
  - Whipple trapezoidal truss, Rensselaer & Saratoga RR, 1853; 35 x 22.5; 38.5 x 24.5; 39 x 25; 3 copies; Print (Folder 41)
    The Whipple trapezoidal truss. Built 1852-53 on the Rensselaer & Saratoga R. R., 7 miles north of Troy, N.Y. [ARB Pl. XVI]
  - Willimansett bridge, 1883-01-29; 25 x 20; Drawing on blueprint paper (Folder 11)
    Connecticut River Railroad Co., Willimansett bridge. Ties and guards
  - Yakima River bridge, 1886; 33 x 31; 30 x 31; Print in two consecutive pieces (Folder 91 a,b)
    300 Feet Span. Combination Bridge over Yakima River. Cascade Div'n, North'n Pacific R.R.. Washington. Buck & McNulty, Engineers.